thule.com 2017-11-18

# Legal and Privacy Policy | Thule | USA

**  
What information does THULE Group collect and how is it used?**  
Thule Group will not collect any personally-identifiable information about you (e.g. your name, address, telephone number or email address) through our website without your knowledge and permission unless you have provided it to us voluntarily.

In order to respond to your questions or fulfill your requests or provide you with our e-newsletter or special offers, it may be necessary to ask for personal information such as your name, address, e-mail address and telephone number. We may use this information to respond to your requests, or to contact you via mail, e-mail or telephone to fulfil your request or provide you with e-newsletter or any other information. Also if you submit personally identifiable information when applying for employment, this information will be collected.

Under the Swedish Personal Data Act (PuL) you have rights of access and rectification in relation to your personal information. Such rights will be adhered to by Thule Group as far as possible to fulfill all of our legal obligations. 

**Your data protection rights**  
You have the right to request access to the personal data which Thule Group processes about you. Moreover, you have the right to request that incorrect or incomplete personal data is corrected. You also have the right to, at any time, withdraw your consent to Thule Group's processing of your personal data, with future effect.

As of the 25 May 2018 you also have, to the extent applicable data protection legislation provides, a right to object to certain processing of personal data, a right to request restriction of the processing of your personal data, and a right to data portability. The right to data portability covers such personal data which Thule Group processes based on an agreement between you and Thule Group or based on your consent, and which you have provided, i.e. name, email, phone number, country, products bought and registered, serial numbers, purchase date and point of purchase. If you have any questions or concerns regarding Thule Group's processing of your personal data, please contact [info@thule.com](mailto:info@thule.com?Subject=Info). Naturally, you also have the right, should you wish, to lodge a complaint with the national data protection authority.

**Does THULE GROUP disclose the stored information to third parties?**  
Thule Group will only store personal information as required to meet legal and regulatory requirements or as needed to provide personalized services to you.

If you provide personally identifiable information to us, we will not disclose your personally identifiable information to any third party without your consent, unless required to do so by law, or unless we in good faith believe such action is necessary to (i) perform a task carried out in the public interest, or (ii) to defend our rights or property or those of any other Thule Group entity or affiliate. However, in order to respond to your questions, fulfil your requests, provide you with specific information, your personally identifiable information may be shared with other Thule Group entities. Any such other Thule Group entity may be located within or outside the European Economic Area. In accordance with the above, if you submit personally identifiable information, you voluntarily consent to transfer of such information to other countries, including countries within or outside of the European Economic Area. 

We do not now or in the future intend to sell, rent or market personal data about you to third parties. 

**W** **hat are cookies?**  
When visiting our website some information may be stored on your computer in the form of a "cookie". A "cookie" is a small text that contains information and is stored on your computer. Cookies are used purely for technical purposes to facilitate use of the web page. One type of cookie saves a file permanently on your computer. It may then be used to personalize a web page according to the user’s choices and interests. The main type of cookie is called a "session cookie". While you are visiting a web page, session cookies are sent between your computer and the server to access information. Session cookies disappear when you turn off your web browser.  A "permanent cookie" is saved to the disk and remains after the browser is closed.

Thule Group uses cookies to gather visitor statistics and to record information about your preferences as you navigate through the web sites. In this way, we hope to be able to better target relevant information to our visitors.

Unless particularly stated elsewhere, cookies are never used by Thule Group with the aim to gather personal data. 

If you do not accept the Thule Group's use of cookies on our web site, it is possible for you to configure your browser to reject cookies by modifying your browser settings. However, this means that we cannot guarantee that all functions of our web site will function as intended. The procedure for rejecting cookies will depend on what web browser you are using. Please consult the information provided with your browser for more information. 

**W** **hat is AddThis?**  
AddThis buttons allows website owners to easily share content with other people either via social networks, e-mail or by bookmarking a page. The buttons provide statistics about bookmarking and sharing activity of users and helps visitors create buzz for sites to increase popularity and ranking. 

**What is Social media?**  
The website might use social media widgets to enable users to engage with content from our websites on various social platforms (Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, LinkedIn etc). To understand how and what information is collected and what cookies are set by these third parties, please refer to the privacy policy of the appropriate social platform.  

**  
Prices on thule.com?**  
Prices listed on thule.com are recommended retail price (RRP). Local variations may apply. Contact your local dealer for more information. 

**How does THULE GROUP protect customer information?**  
Thule Group maintains high standards to safeguard your personal information at all times, and will carefully protect all such information.

All passwords are encrypted and our servers are protected by secure fire walls.  

**D** **** **oes the Privacy Policy of Thule Group apply on linked external websites?**  
Our website may contain links to other websites such as benefit providers. These Third party websites are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. If you access other websites using the links provided, the operators of these websites may collect your personal information. Please ensure that you are satisfied with the Privacy Policy of these Third Parties before you submit any personal information.  

**Extranet user handling**  
Logins to Thule group Extranets are personal and a personal email address is used for identification. A user that is connected to a dealer/point of sales will get the information settings chosen for that dealer/point of sales. It is the responsibility of the Extranet Administrator for a specific dealer/point of sales to remove any rights for a user that should no longer have access to the Extranet on behalf of the dealer/point of sales.

Other Thule Group brands may use the same user data and this is also the case for the Thule group Extranet. The extranet spans all brands.  

**How does Thule Group update this Privacy Policy?**  
Thule Group may at any time without any notice revise the terms of this Private Policy by updating it. We recommend that visitors to our website re-visit the Privacy policy of Thule Group on occasion to learn of new Privacy practices or changes to our policy. 

**Trademark and copyright**  
A trademark is a word, logotype, slogan, colour or shape that identifies and distinguishes the source or origin of a product or service.  All trademarks belonging to Thule Group are important and valuable assets of the company.

The Thule Group respects the Intellectual Property rights of others, and we ask the same of others. 

Unless otherwise indicated on this site, all trademarks, brand names and corporate logos are the property of Thule Group or its affiliates and protected by Intellectual Property Rights Law.

Trademarks, brand names and corporate logos belonging to Thule Group may not be used in any way without the prior written permission from Thule Group. 

The copyright of this website, including without limitation, all documents, files, text, images, graphics, devices, sound, audio-visual elements, is owned by Thule Group and is protected by Swedish and international copyright laws. (All Rights Reserved)

The website or any part of it may not, apart from what is stated below, be reproduced, duplicated, copied, transferred, distributed, stored or otherwise exploited for any commercial use without prior written permission by Thule Group. No links to this website may be included in any other website without the prior written permission by Thule Group. Modifications to the contents on this website are expressly prohibited. 

You are authorized to view, print and copy any document published on this website for your personal non-commercial use and provided that any such copy or print retains all copyright or other proprietary notices. 

You are authorized to use information from this website if it is only used for information purposes, provided the source of information is mentioned. You may copy and print press releases and other documents classified as public. 

The content of the information may not be modified and the information should be used in a way that does not harm the reputation of Thule Group. 

The website may contain images that are subject to copyright of third parties.  

**Contact**  
In case you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please don't hesitate to contact customer support through this web site.

**D** **isclaimer**  
Although every care has been taken to assure the accuracy of the information on the website of Thule Group, we provide this information "as is" and disclaim all warranties, expressed or implied, that the information supplied is accurate, complete or current. You acknowledge that your use of the website including, but not limited to, the use of any links on the website and of the information supplied on the website is at your sole risk. Further, Thule Group assumes no responsibility for the content on any third party websites and any links to such on the website are provided only to facilitate you. All material, including but not limited to, text, photographs, graphics and figures on any Thule Group website may contain technical errors or typing inaccuracies or other types of errors or inaccuracies. Neither Thule Group nor any company associated with Thule Group assumes any responsibility whatsoever for any such errors or inaccuracies. 

This applies also to the "Buyer’s Guide" on this website and any outcome thereof, which is supplied solely as a service, for information purposes only, and which do not contain any advice or recommendation that may be relied upon as the basis for any decision or action. All data and information supplied through the "Buyer’s Guide" derive from testing of Thule products on specific third party products. Technical components and performance quality etc. of such third party products and parts thereof may at any time following the Thule Group testing be altered (without the involvement or knowledge of Thule Group). Consequently, neither Thule Group nor any company associated with Thule Group shall (unless otherwise explicitly provided for under mandatory legislation) be liable for property damage or personal injury caused by the use of a Thule product which deviates from any instruction guide or user manual that (i) accompanies the Thule product at purchase thereof or (ii) applies to the product(s) on which the Thule product shall be fitted on or used together with. Prior to the use of each Thule product, Thule Group encourages you to thoroughly read each such instruction guide or user manual.

Further, Thule Group explicitly disclaims any warranty that any website of Thule Group is free from infection by virus or anything else that has contaminating or destructive properties or that the information on any Thule Group website will be uninterruptible or error free. 

Neither Thule Group nor any person or company associated with Thule Group shall be liable for any damage whatsoever resulting from your use or inability to use this website or any information, content, services, or materials provided by or on this website. 

Thule Group reserves the right to amend, add and/or exclude any information on the website (including this disclaimer) at any time and without any prior notice thereof. Thule Group shall not be obliged to update this website, including any information on the website.
